Guide to the Christina Rossetti Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Christina Rossetti collection
1854-1882
GEN MSS 267
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.2
(1 box)
Letters by Christina Rossetti to various parties, including William Bryant and Frederic James Shields. Included in a letter to William Edmonstoune Aytoun are manuscripts of six poems.
Rossetti, Christina Georgina, 1830-1894
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ongoing collection of documents acquired by gift and purchase from various sources. Type of accession (gift or purchase) and date of acquisition is noted in the box-and-folder list. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses accessions of single manuscripts and small groups of manuscripts and other papers, by or pertaining to Christina Rossetti, which the library has chosen to group and list as an artificial collection. Materials incorporated into the collection prior to June 1997 have been organized into one series: Correspondence.
Authors, English -- 19th century; Aytoun, William Edmondstoune, 1813-1865; Rossetti, Christina Georgina, 1830-1894; Shields, Frederic, 1833-1911
- I. Correspondence
  - ROSSETTI, CHRISTINA
    - ALS to William Edmondstoune Aytoun, London, 1854 Aug 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Enclosure: Autograph MS of six poems submitted by Christina Rossetti to Mr. Aytoun, editor of "The Athenaeum": Symbols; Something like truth; Easter Even; The watcher; Once; Long enough
      Purchase, 1954
    - ALS to [William] Bryant, [London], [1882 Apr] (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Removed from her New Poems. London and New York, 1896.
      Gift, 1984
    - 9 ALS to William Bryant, London, 1886-8 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Gift, 1961
    - ALS to Mr. Bryant, [London] (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Gift, 1983
    - ALS to Mrs. Bryant, London, n.y. Monday (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Purchase, 1958
    - ALS to Mrs. Gilchrist, London, n.y. Tuesday (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - ALS to Mrs. Heimann, Gloucester, 1869 May 31 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Gift, 1954
    - 2 ALS to Frederic James Shields, London (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - ALS to an unidentified correspondent, London, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Gift, 1947
    - ALS to an unidentified recipient, London, n.y. Friday (Box 1, Folder 10)
      From a collection formed by George Bainton and William Michael Rossetti. Gift, 1957
    - ALS to an unidentified recipient, London (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Purchase, 1957